NGUYEN MANH NGUYEN

✓ nguyennm1024@gmail.com

♀ Hanoi, Vietnam **८**(84)-981-787-656

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interest lies in how to make machine learning models which can understand both vision and language information, reasoning and extract knowledge from images and videos. Specifically, my works focus on extract text information from videos and images.

EDUCATION

University of Engineering and Technology - Vietnam National University

Aug 2016 - Aug 2020

Bachelor of Information Technology

GPA: 3.31/4.0

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

VinAI Research

Dec 2019 - Now

AI Research Resident

- Supervisor: Prof. Minh Hoai Nguyen (google scholar)
- 1. Proposing a new approach to improve h-mean score of state-of-the-art scene text spotting backbones using language prior. This method can be used in both training and testing phases, which is improving many different backbones. This work has been accepted in **CVPR 2021**.
- 2. Introducing a novel Vietnamese scene text dataset (VinText) the largest scene text dataset in Vietnam with 2000 fully annotated images and about 56.000 text instances.

VinAI Research May 2021 - Sep 2021

Applied Rotation Program

- 1. Collecting a text street signs dataset in videos. Proposing a reasonably priced annotation method but still maintaining data quality.
- 2. Developing a novel text traffic signs recognition pipeline and improving inference speed.

Artificial Intelligence and Multimedia Signal Processing Lab, UET-VNU

Jun 2018 - Mar 2020

Research Assistant

- Supervisor: Prof. Hoang Van Xiem (google scholar)
- 1. Using machine learning to speed up quad-tree partitioning and enhance decoded frame quality.
- 2. Co-supervising junior students and helping them to develop their project: ID card information extraction.

PUBLICATIONS

Dictionary-guided Scene Text Recognition

2021

Nguyen Nguyen, Thu Nguyen, Vinh Tran, Minh Triet-Tran, Thanh Duc Ngo, Thien Huu Nguyen, Minh Hoai Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, 2021.

INDUSTRIAL EXPERIENCE

Teko Vietnam Apr. 2019 - Nov. 2019

AI Engineer Intern

- 1. Exploring e-commerce problems and using AI for several tasks: Product clustering, Customer segmentation, Automatic keywords generation.
- 2. Working with e-commerce big data system, write API service, build web-based tool to analyze products, and setup CI/CD

PINGCOM Sep. 2018 - Jan. 2019

AI Engineer Intern

- 1. Setting up Cassandra and PySpark with docker to manage Facebook data of over 100.000 users.
- 2. Developing name2gender models to predict gender from user names, then write an API using Flask

Text traffic signs recognition

- Collecting a video text street sign dataset in Vietnam, proposing methods to annotate data more efficiently, and validating data quality. Developing deep learning models to recognize text in street signs and incorporating it into traffic sign recognition system for autopilot.
- Tools: Pytorch, OpenCV.

Scene text spotting

- Proposing a novel approach to incorporate knowledge from dictionary in both training and testing stages. This approach helps many models improve themselves without complexity increment in inference phase. I also built an annotation tool for data collection and introduce a novel Vietnamese scene text dataset (VinText) and publicize it for community.
- Tools: Pytorch, OpenCV, javascript

Product Clustering

- Representing Phong Vu product data by attributes and product descriptions, building an automated pipeline from data collection, feature selection, dimensionality reduction with VAE, and clustering. I also built a dashboard to visualize products for analysis.
- Tools: PySpark, Bokeh, Scikit learn, Keras, Tensorflow, Pandas, Matplotlib, SciPy.

Automatic keywords generation

- Developing a system that can automatically generate keywords for products using titles and descriptions.
- Tools: PySpark, Scikit learn, Pandas, Matplotlib, SciPy.

Automatic keywords generation

- Developing a module that takes people's real name or Facebook nickname as input and outputs their predicted gender.
- Tools: Python, Scikit-learn, Flask.

GUI Automation Testing

- Developing a UI automatic testing tool for Windows OS applications
- Tools: C#, Microsoft UIAutomation, WPF

AWARD

The Excellence Scholarship

2020

University of Engineering and Technology - Vietnam National University

Top 8/400 students in the final academic year

Research Competition Award

2018

University of Engineering and Technology - Vietnam National University

Third prize in the UET-VNU research competition

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Python, C/C++

Software & Tools: Machine learning: Pytorch, Keras, Scikit learn, MLlib

Computer vision: OpenCV

Data engineering: PySpark, Pandas, Matplotlib, Numpy, Flask

Tools: Bokeh, Git, Docker

ACTIVITIES

Competition jury member

2021

Ho Chi Minh city AI Challenge 2021: Vietnamese Scene Text Recognition

Invited speaker 2021

Public computer vision workshop organized by VinAI Reseasrch

Teaching Assistant Jun 2018 - April 2019

University of Engineering and Technology - Vietnam National University

Teaching assistant in several computer vision and machine learning courses for Samsung Display Vietnam's staff